<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
	<channel>
		<title>ARCoach </title>
		<link>https://i.cs.hku.hk/~msp19047/</link>
		<generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
		<language>en-us</language>
		<author></author>
		<rights>Copyright (c) 1</rights>
		<updated>0001-01-01 00:00:00 &#43;0000 UTC</updated>
		
		<item>
			<title>Calendar</title>
			<link>https://i.cs.hku.hk/~msp19047/calendar/</link>
			<pubDate>Wed, 01 Jul 2020 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
			<author></author>
			<guid>https://i.cs.hku.hk/~msp19047/calendar/</guid>
			<media:content xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://i.cs.hku.hk/~msp19047/img/Calendar.jpg" medium="image" type="image/jpg" width="100" height="100" />
			<description>&lt;p&gt;The plan tab page of ARCoach is designed to display a highly customizable calendar and users can check or add the workouts for the specific day through the calendar. ARCoach uses JTCalendar plugin as a customized calendar to achieve the above features. JTCalendar supports week view mode and limits date range by defining a start and an end to the calendar. When the user clicks the date in the calendar, corresponding added workouts would be displayed below the calendar.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To store the scheduled workouts together with dates, the database schema is designed according to dates. After the user adds a workout and clicks the save button, the information about this plan would be uploaded into the cloud database under the path of uid-trainPlan-yyyymmdd-workout.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After the user adding a workout and clicking the save button, ARCoach would return to the plan tab page and read data from the database again to refresh the content. However, there is a time delay for the cloud database in practice, in other words, the plan tab page may not show the workouts previously added. To avoid this delay, ARCoach saves data both in the local array and online database, uses the local array to refresh data, and uses the online database to save data permanently.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Below are the screenshots of the plan tab page. The calendar shows recent one-month dates with today&amp;rsquo;s date as default. There is an add button at the right up corner, which would direct to add the workout page. In add the workout page, users select different workouts through the picker, the image of workouts would change as the picker rotates.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;../img/CalendarScreenshot.png&#34; alt=&#34;Screenshots of Calendar&#34;&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Screenshots of Calendar&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Read next: &lt;a href=&#34;https://i.cs.hku.hk/~msp19047/~msp19047/plank&#34;&gt;Plank Detection&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
		</item>
		
		<item>
			<title>Quantification of Performance</title>
			<link>https://i.cs.hku.hk/~msp19047/performance/</link>
			<pubDate>Wed, 24 Jun 2020 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
			<author></author>
			<guid>https://i.cs.hku.hk/~msp19047/performance/</guid>
			<media:content xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://i.cs.hku.hk/~msp19047/img/Performance.png" medium="image" type="image/jpg" width="100" height="100" />
			<description>&lt;p&gt;ARCoach gives the users feedback about the exercise through hints and a performance score. The judgment of the performance score should be related to the professional coaches&amp;rsquo; corresponding exercise. ARCoach borrows the idea from MSE (mean square error).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Take jumping jacks as an example. ARCoach judges the performance by MSE value, more close MSE is to 0, more accurate the exercise.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;../img/MSE.png&#34; alt=&#34;MSE&#34;&gt;
&lt;em&gt;MSE&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;../img/Performance.png&#34; alt=&#34;Quantification of Performance&#34;&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Quantification of Performance&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Read next: &lt;a href=&#34;https://i.cs.hku.hk/~msp19047/~msp19047/calendar&#34;&gt;Calendar&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
		</item>
		
		<item>
			<title>Squats Detection</title>
			<link>https://i.cs.hku.hk/~msp19047/squats/</link>
			<pubDate>Wed, 24 Jun 2020 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
			<author></author>
			<guid>https://i.cs.hku.hk/~msp19047/squats/</guid>
			<media:content xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://i.cs.hku.hk/~msp19047/img/Squats.png" medium="image" type="image/jpg" width="100" height="100" />
			<description>&lt;p&gt;It can be concluded that the position between the user and iPhone would affect the joint data of Squats from the below figure. Considered that part of the joint data is heavily impacted by the position, the algorithm should choose the joint data which has a clear &amp;ldquo;wave pattern&amp;rdquo; to determine a valid exercise count accurately. ARCoach chooses the hand joints and foot joints on axis-Y to detect a valid count, plus hand joints and foot joints on axis-Z to calculate the performance score of Squat workout.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;../img/Position.png&#34; alt=&#34;Position&#34;&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Different position between the user and iPhone&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The absolute values of two hands or feet are almost identical in the same direction. If the maximum of RHY(where RHY means “Right-Hand joint data on Y-axis” etc) and LHY together with a maximum of RFY and LFY are regarded as a beginning of squats, the next appearance of these combinations roughly stands for the ending of squats.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If certain interval elapses and there is no sign of iconic extremum, it means that the hip is not qualified in the height standards, the hint logically should be “squat lower” then restart the count down timer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Read next: &lt;a href=&#34;https://i.cs.hku.hk/~msp19047/~msp19047/performance&#34;&gt;Quantification of Performance&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
		</item>
		
		<item>
			<title>Jumping Jacks Detection</title>
			<link>https://i.cs.hku.hk/~msp19047/jumping-jacks/</link>
			<pubDate>Wed, 17 Jun 2020 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
			<author></author>
			<guid>https://i.cs.hku.hk/~msp19047/jumping-jacks/</guid>
			<media:content xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://i.cs.hku.hk/~msp19047/img/JumpingJacks.png" medium="image" type="image/jpg" width="100" height="100" />
			<description>&lt;p&gt;ARKit framework provides the captured skeleton of a person from iPhone&amp;rsquo;s back camera in real-time. Detailed three-dimensional joint data can be extracted from the skeleton such as the distance of Right Hand Joint with respect to Root / Hip Joint. Below are the skeleton and some of the joints.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;../img/Skeleton.png&#34; alt=&#34;skeleton&#34;&gt;
&lt;em&gt;skeleton&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;ARKit uses a right-handed coordinate system where the direction of view is along the negative Z-axis, as illustrated below.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;../img/Coordinate.png&#34; alt=&#34;coordinate&#34;&gt;
&lt;em&gt;coordinate&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In order to explore the pattern of jumping jacks, a video of a professional coach doing jumping jacks is fed into the ARKit framework. As a simple start, 6 kinds of data are chosen where LHX means &amp;ldquo;Left-Hand joint data on X-axis&amp;rdquo; etc. From the data, it can be concluded that a jumping jack has a certain pattern and the absolute value of two hands are almost identical in the same direction. If the minimum of RHY and LHY are regarded as a beginning of jumping jacks, the next appearance of minimum roughly stands for the ending of jumping jacks. In this way, the algorithm detects the minimum and maximum, combines the joint data of the left/right hand on X-axis and Y-axis to create a threshold. If the derived condition is satisfied, lead to a valid count of exercise the count label would increase by one. The above solution can recognize the same exercise at varying pace.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;../img/JumpingJacksData.png&#34; alt=&#34;jumpingJacksData&#34;&gt;
&lt;em&gt;jumpingJacksData&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The time and count would be frozen when the pause button is pressed and would be unfrozen when the resume button is pressed. The stop button would save and upload this training record into the cloud database and then return to the Workout Page. Below is the screenshot of the Jumping Jacks Detection Page.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;../img/JumpingJacksScreenshot.png&#34; alt=&#34;JumpingJacksScreenshot&#34;&gt;
&lt;em&gt;JumpingJacksScreenshot&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of the unique features of ARCoach is instant fitness instructions. When to raise a hint and what the content of a hint becoming an important issue during the exercise time. The basic idea is to detect the beginning of jumping jacks, the timer starts the count down. If certain interval elapses and there is no sign of iconic extremum, it means that the arms are not qualified in the height standards, the hint logically should be &amp;ldquo;raise arms higher&amp;rdquo; then restart the count down timer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;../img/Hint.png&#34; alt=&#34;Hint&#34;&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Hint&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Read next: &lt;a href=&#34;https://i.cs.hku.hk/~msp19047/~msp19047/squats&#34;&gt;Squats Detection&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
		</item>
		
		<item>
			<title>UI Design</title>
			<link>https://i.cs.hku.hk/~msp19047/ui-design/</link>
			<pubDate>Thu, 11 Jun 2020 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
			<author></author>
			<guid>https://i.cs.hku.hk/~msp19047/ui-design/</guid>
			<media:content xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://i.cs.hku.hk/~msp19047/img/UIDesign.jpg" medium="image" type="image/jpg" width="100" height="100" />
			<description>&lt;p&gt;The Login, Register, and Edit Profile page are shown below. Registration requires name, password, gender, age, weight, height, and email. Login asks for a valid registered email and the correct password. In the Edit Profile page, users are allowed to edit all information except for email. Users can upload a picture from iPhone’s gallery or take a picture as their profile pictures.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;../img/RegisterPage.png&#34; alt=&#34;Login, Register, and Edit Profile page&#34;&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Login, Register, and Edit Profile page&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;ARCoach can be divided into 4 major parts, namely Activity, Plan, Workouts, and Me. Below are the screenshots of each tab bar page.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;../img/MainPage.png&#34; alt=&#34;Activity, Plan, Workouts, and Me page&#34;&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Activity, Plan, Workouts, and Me page&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the Activity page, ARCoach would access health data from iPhone through HealthKit and display them. It also would grab history data of training minutes and training days from Firebase.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the Plan page, JTAppleCalendar is displayed. It can be scrolled to select the date. In the future, ARCoach would link the date and training plan together​(TO-DO)​.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the Activity page, instead of just playing a video that instructs users how to do the exercise, ARCoach would combine AR and VR technology, analyze the motion based on motion tracking results in order to give feedback to users. The algorithm would make use of important joints of the body, such as right hand, right shoulder, head, hip, right foot joints. By analyzing the relationship between the joints, to determine whether the users have done the workouts correctly​(TO-DO)​.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the Me page, it records the personal information related to sport and display the profile picture and user’s name. The setting button on the top right would direct the user to the Edit Profile page.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Read next: &lt;a href=&#34;https://i.cs.hku.hk/~msp19047/~msp19047/jumping-jacks&#34;&gt;JumpingJacks Detection&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
		</item>
		
		<item>
			<title>Database</title>
			<link>https://i.cs.hku.hk/~msp19047/database/</link>
			<pubDate>Wed, 10 Jun 2020 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
			<author></author>
			<guid>https://i.cs.hku.hk/~msp19047/database/</guid>
			<media:content xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://i.cs.hku.hk/~msp19047/img/Firebase.png" medium="image" type="image/jpg" width="100" height="100" />
			<description>&lt;p&gt;ARCoach uses Firebase as authentication and database. User registers in ARCoach and ARCoach would send the user’s email and password to Firebase and get a complicated UID in return. The user’s information would be uploaded into Firebase realtime database under the root of the user’s UID. The free version of Firebase supports up to 100 connections simultaneously.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;../img/Architecture.png&#34; alt=&#34;Architecture&#34;&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Architecture of ARCoach&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The authentication in Firebase is shown below. It includes an email address as an ID and an auto-generated UID.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;../img/Firebase_Authentication.png&#34; alt=&#34;Firebase Authentication&#34;&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Firebase Authentication&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The user’s information is stored under the root of the corresponding UID. For example, under the UID tLo3EXZPbXea6I69kuXbq5WQI873, there are two nodes named profile and profilePicture. Profile node saves basic information such as age, email, gender, height, weight, and name. ProfilePicture node saves the URL of the profile picture which is stored in Firebase Storage.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;../img/Firebase_Realtime_Database.png&#34; alt=&#34;Firebase Realtime  Database&#34;&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Firebase Realtime Database&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Read next: &lt;a href=&#34;https://i.cs.hku.hk/~msp19047/~msp19047/ui-design&#34;&gt;UI Design&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
		</item>
		
		<item>
			<title>About ARCoach</title>
			<link>https://i.cs.hku.hk/~msp19047/about-arcoach/</link>
			<pubDate>Tue, 09 Jun 2020 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
			<author></author>
			<guid>https://i.cs.hku.hk/~msp19047/about-arcoach/</guid>
			<media:content xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://i.cs.hku.hk/~msp19047/img/ARCoach.png" medium="image" type="image/jpg" width="100" height="100" />
			<description>&lt;p&gt;This project aims to develop an iOS application ARCoach for giving instant fitness instructions and feedbacks armed with body motion tracking through the iPhone’s camera, providing exercises with virtual objects using immersive technology Augmented Reality(AR). It helps users to do exercises correctly at home without hiring a coach or buying extra wearable devices, meanwhile enjoy the immersive experience brought by AR.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Unlike some fitness applications that need input data from a wearable device, ARCoach uses the camera of iPhone to track body motion and extract movement information, users, therefore, need not buy an extra wearable device for fitness. Besides, ARCoach takes advantage of the powerful ARKit Framework of iOS and corresponding Apple device’s support, thus it improves interaction and creates a virtually fun environment for users. ARCoach gives instructions of indoor exercise includes Lunges, Crunch, Push up, Sit up and Squat, it tracks movements of users in real-time and produces a 3D skeleton. It analyses the data of 3D skeleton joints, compares with the recordings data from the professional coaches in order to give instructions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Read next: &lt;a href=&#34;https://i.cs.hku.hk/~msp19047/~msp19047/database&#34;&gt;Database&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
		</item>
		
	</channel>
</rss>
